scholastic.ca 2003-02-07

# Scholastic Canada: Privacy Policy

**PRIVACY NOTICE**

The Privacy Notice is an agreement between Scholastic Canada Ltd. and visitors of our site. If you do not agree to the terms of this policy, please do not use this site. The following policy applies to the Scholastic.ca site. 

Scholastic Canada Ltd. is committed to protecting the privacy and security of its online visitors. This policy statement provides our visitors (e.g., parents, teachers and children) with an overview of the measures we have taken to provide a safe environment for everyone. 

**PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**

We only collect personally identifiable information from our visitors 13 years old or above when such visitors voluntarily submit such information. 

With respect to visitors under 13 years of age, we do not collect personally identifiable information without first obtaining verifiable parental consent, unless we only use such information to: (1) obtain parental consent or provide parents with notice that we have collected information from their children; (2) respond directly on a one-time basis to a child's specific request; (3) respond more than once to a child's specific request along with providing parental notice of such use; (4) protect the safety of a child; or (5) comply with legal requirements. The consent and notification process mentioned above gives parents the ability to let us know if they do not want us to make further use of the personally identifiable information we have collected from their child. 

We consider the following, among other things, to be personally identifiable information: first and last name, e-mail address, street address and phone number. We may request such personally identifiable information from children in connection with our contests, sweepstakes, games, surveys, forums, subscription registrations, content submissions, classroom activities, requests for suggestions, and visitors' requests for free products, services (such as our magazines) or additional information. We collect such information so that we can contact a winner, answer questions or requests, and fulfil orders, as applicable. Unless we indicate otherwise, personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 will be used solely by Scholastic Canada Ltd. or its agents for internal purposes and will not be sold or otherwise transferred to third parties. 

It is Scholastic Canada Ltd.'s policy never to post on its site, more than a child's first name, first initial of last name, province and age or grade. 

**FOR PARENTS**

There are many activities on the Scholastic Canada Ltd. site that children can participate in and enjoy without having to share personally identifiable information. 

For those activities that require personally identifiable information, such as contests and sweepstakes (in compliance Canada's federal privacy law, the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act), Scholastic Canada Ltd. will not condition a child's participation in an activity on that child disclosing more personally identifiable information than is reasonably necessary to administer the activity. For certain online activities, we require verifiable parental consent before collecting or using a child's personally identifiable information. With these activities, Scholastic will notify the respective parent (by mail, fax) of our privacy policy and obtain verifiable parental consent before collecting personally identifiable information from a child, unless one of the exceptions discussed above applies. 

Parents can request to review, amend, update or have deleted their child's personally identifiable information from Scholastic Canada Ltd.'s records, and refuse to permit further use of a child's information by printing, completing and returning 

_this letter_ by fax or regular mail to the specified address. 

**FOR TEACHERS**

There are many activities on the Scholastic Canada Ltd. site that are for teachers, which enable teachers to add another dimension to their classroom and students' activities. We use information we collect from you about your preferences to help us improve our web site so that it continually responds to the interests of our visitors. 

**FOR KIDS**

Remember to be smart online. Do not give out your full name, e-mail address, home address, telephone number or any other personal information that would enable someone to contact you either online or offline, without first asking your parent or guardian for permission. Sometimes on our site we will ask you for your first name and e-mail address, along with your parent's e-mail or home address. We do this so that we can contact your parent to let them know that you have communicated with us and that we have collected this information from you. 

**NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION AND THE USE OF COOKIE TECHNOLOGY**

We collect non-personally identifiable information through the use of a software technology called "cookies", and through our visitor's voluntary submissions to us and/or upon our request. By non-personally identifiable information, we are referring to information about our visitor's browser (e.g., Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer), operating systems (e.g., Windows or Macintosh), Internet service providers (e.g., AOL or NET.COM) and other similar information which we track in aggregate form. We also collect the following non-personally identifiable information in connection with content submissions, games, classrooms and bulletin boards: first name only and first initial of last name, Province, age and grade. The non-personally identifiable information that we track is anonymous and will never be identified with or lead us back to any of our visitors. 

Cookie technology helps us to know how many people visit us and where visitors go on our site. Cookies are small bits of information we send to your computer. Among other things, this non-personally identifiable information allows us to know which areas are favourites, which areas need a bit of improvement, or what technologies and Internet services are being used by our visitors, so that we may continually improve our visitor's online experiences. 

**USE OF IP ADDRESSES**

We collect IP addresses to obtain aggregate information on the use of Scholastic.ca. An IP address is a number assigned to your computer by a Web server when you're on the web. When you are on our site, we have a back-end server which logs your computer's IP address. We only use the information we find out from tracking IP addresses in the aggregate, such as how many users entered a specific area of our site, and not to track a specific IP address to identify an individual user. However, we may use such information to identify a user if we feel that there are or may be safety and/or security issues, or to comply with legal requirements. 

**SECURITY**

Scholastic Canada Ltd. ensures that all information, personally and non-personally identifiable information, that it receives via the Internet is secure against unauthorised access. This information is kept in a safe and secure system, isolated from direct connection to the Internet. This means that no eyes but ours will ever see the information that our visitors send to us, unless we indicate otherwise. 

In some places on our site, parents and teachers may be able to purchase items with the use of a credit card. In such instances, Scholastic Canada Ltd. uses secure server software over a Secure Socket Layer (SSL) line, the latest technology to protect your credit card information. SSL is the industry standard and among the best software available today for secure commerce transactions. It encrypts all of your credit card information so that the information from your credit card cannot be read as it travels over the Internet. 

**LINKS TO OTHER SITES**

Visitors will find links from Scholastic.ca to independently owned, controlled and/or managed World Wide Web or Internet sites whose content we have found of possible interest to our visitors. In many cases, but not always, the links represent co-operative projects or mutual links established with the organisations connected with these sites. While we initially visit these sites to which we directly link, please note that we do not monitor or control the content that appears on these sites and such content may be constantly changing. We recommend that children check with their parents or teachers before clicking off to any new sites, and we encourage children and parents to read the privacy policies of all linked sites before navigating through them. 

Please note that we may revise our above policy as the content on our sites continues to change. 

We hope that you enjoy exploring our site. 

Scholastic.ca is owned and operated by Scholastic Canada Ltd., 175 Hillmount Road, Markham, Ontario, Canada L6C 1Z7. We can be reached by phone at 905-887-7323, by fax at 905-887-1131 and by e-mail at 

[_custserve@scholastic.ca_](mailto:custserve@scholastic.ca). If you have any questions about our privacy policy or practices, or you wish to amend, update or verify the information on file, or notify us that you want your information deleted from our files, please contact the Web Producer at this address. 

**GetNetWise**

GetNetWise is an online resource that provides information and tools that parents and teachers can use to guide children to a safe online experience. You can access this content by clicking on the GetNetWise logo below. This initiative is part of an industry effort to create an online environment where adults feel empowered with tools, information and resources to safeguard children online. 

**ICRA**

The Internet Content Rating Association is an international, independent organization that empowers the public, especially parents, to make informed decisions about electronic media by means of the open and objective labelling of content. ICRA's dual aims are to: 

  * protect children from potentially harmful material; and, 
  * to protect free speech on the internet.
